把目标定得比你以为的极限还离谱 10 倍
Aim for something that seems 10x more ridiculous than you ever think it could,
它大概能完成其中的 90%
and it probably can do 90% of it.
在 OpenAI 办公室里，你从这头走到那头
You cannot walk from point A to point B in the OpenAI office without hearing Codex
一天里总会听到有人提起 Codex
get mentioned over the course of the day,
有了 Codex，我的产出大概是原来的三到四倍
I'm probably doing 3 or 4x more than I would have without Codex.
Codex 其实知道怎么给自己搭建自动化，然后直接把结果给你
Codex actually knows how to set up its own automation. It just comes back to you.
它在做的时候，你根本不用去操心它在做什么
You didn't have to think about what it was doing while it was doing it.
这真的不再是“什么才有可能”的问题了
It's literally not a question of what is possible.
一切皆有可能，问题只在于我们该做什么
It's just everything is possible. It's just what should we do?
好，那我们先从宏观层面聊起吧
All right, so why don't we start by talking at a high level.
我自己也做了十多年 PM，很多工作
You know, I've been a PM for over a decade too, and, and like a lot of the work,
说白了就是改 Google Docs、做计划
dude, it's just like, you know, editing Google Docs, making plans,
开对齐会议，都是这类事，对吧？
doing alignment meetings, like all this kind of stuff, right?
那 Codex 从根本上改变了你作为 PM 的工作方式吗？
But like, how has Codex fundamentally transformed how you work as a PM?
我会说，它从两个层面改变了我们
I would say that there's two levers by which it's changing how we work
作为产品经理的工作方式
as product managers.
一个是我们具体怎么做这份工作
One is the actual how we do the specifics of the job,
其次是现在整个团队，工程师
but then secondarily is that now with the entire team, you know, engineers,
产品经理、设计师，都在用 Codex
product managers, designers, all using Codex,
每个人扮演的角色都变得有点不一样了
it's just the role that everyone's playing is slightly different.
所以不只是用不同的方式做以前的事
And so it's not just doing the old stuff differently,
连我们整体的运作方式都很不一样了
but even just the way we operate is very different.
呃，我觉得，从根本上说，很多
Uh, I think that, I mean, fundamentally, I would say a lot of,
如果你看看产品经理过去一直在做的事
if you look at what product managers were historically doing, what we've been up to,
就是大量的信息整合
it's a lot of information synthesis
以及围绕和不同客户的各种互动来形成想法
and kind of building ideas around lots of different interactions with different customers.
我觉得至少在 OpenAI，我们产品这边人手很精简
And I think that at least at OpenAI, we are pretty light on the product side.
在 Codex 这边，我们只有几个 PM
You know, on Codex, we only have a few PMs, um,
要负责很多不同的领域
working across a lot of different areas.
所以从根本上说，这只有靠 Codex 才做得到
And so fundamentally this is only possible because of Codex.
打个底吧，我们每天会收到成千上万的
Got a baseline level. You know, we get thousands of,
每天大概有几百个不同的
every day there's probably hundreds of different
问题、数据点或 bug，来自企业客户
problems or data points or bugs that we're getting from enterprise customers or,
当然还有 Twitter 上的用户等等
you know, obviously customers on Twitter and things like this.
所以在最前端这一步
And so I'd say at the the front end of this,
Codex 在整合海量信息上非常有价值
it's Codex is extremely valuable for just synthesizing tons of information
让像我这样的人能够在比以前多得多的上下文下工作
and kind of enabling someone like myself to operate with way more context than I
这是以前做不到的
would have been able to previously.
我可能临时被拉进一个全新的项目，20 分钟内
I'll be added last minute onto an entirely new project that I, in 20 minutes,
就能立刻掌握我加入之前发生的全部上下文
can immediately just have all of the context of stuff happened before I joined,
因为 Codex 能接入我们所有的工具，都连在一起
you know, because Codex can go into all of our tools, connected into things.
Slack、Notion、Linear、email 和 Google Drive
Slack and Notion and Linear and email and Google Drive.
呃，所以我觉得每个人，尤其是产品经理
Um, and so I think that everybody, especially the product managers,
都能够更加，呃
just are able to be way more, uh,
高效借力，快速切入不同的事情
leveraged and like quickly jump into different things. Um,
然后我想说，实际上
and then I would say the actual, you know,
除了能用这些信息做决策之外
beyond just being able to make decisions with that information,
我们生成各种产出物的方式也彻底变了，对吧？
it's all of the ways that we generate artifacts have fundamentally changed, right?
不管是幻灯片、原型、文档、PRD
Whether it's slides, uh, you know, prototypes, docs, PRDs,
所有这些东西，我觉得现在，很多这些
all of these things I think are now either a lot of these things
以前需要花很多力气的事，现在其实都能靠自动化搞定
that previously required a lot of effort now can actually be done via automation.
呃，是的，所以这让我们能把更多时间真正花在
Um, yeah, so then it allows us to actually just spend a lot more time focusing on
决策，以及好好把事情想透
decision making and kind of thinking through things
更重要的是，多和客户交流
and kind of we're talking to customers more importantly.
所以，呃，我很乐意，我们可以深入聊
So, um, yeah, I mean, happy to, we can dig up.
它改变了很多不同的方面
There's a lot of different ways that it's changed.
但从根本上说，我觉得我们只是把更多时间花在
But I think fundamentally, I think we're just spending a lot more time doing the
更重要的事上，也就是和客户交流
more important stuff, which is talking to customers
以及和团队一起打造产品
and working with our teams to build product
而花在那些手工琐事上的时间少了很多。是啊，兄弟，那
and a lot less time doing a lot of the more manual stuff. Yeah, dude, there,
现在有个梗在流传，说这些规划是给 agents 看的
there's like a meme going around. That like, uh, the plans are for agents.
甚至已经不是给人看的了
They're not even for humans anymore.
而且你知道，兄弟，就是
So, and you know, dude, like, there's like
以前浪费了太多时间去写这些，比如写 10 页的
so much time wasted on just like writing these like in the old days writing 10 page
PRD，或者长期战略之类的东西
PRDs or like long term strategy or whatever.
我真的很好奇，因为我知道 Codex 团队非常拼
Like I'm I'm really curious because I know the Codex team works really hard
而且推进得很快
and moves very fast.
所以你们到底做多少规划
So like how, how much planning do you guys do
Codex 又是怎么参与到这个过程里的？
and like how how is Codex involved in the process?
我想说，总体上在 OpenAI，我们都是
I mean, we're definitely I'd say in general being at OpenAI, we are all,
我们运作得非常像一个研究实验室，连做产品的方式也是
we operate very much a research lab. Even how we develop product.
所以我们一直在
And so we're constantly, you know,
不断尝试，所以我们不会提前六个月去规划
trying things and so we're not planning things out six months in advance.
我觉得我一直，我也不知道怎么说才对，我一直
I think I've, I've, I don't know what the right, I've always,
我一直在想我们需要一个新的
I've been thinking we need a new, new,
一个替代 roadmap 的新词，因为 roadmap 暗示的是 12 个月的规划
a new word for roadmap because roadmap kind of implies this 12 month out thing.
我觉得更像是四到八周的计划
I think it's more what's the four to eight week plan?
我们知道那些优先级是什么，然后照着执行
We know what those priorities are and let's execute against those.
然后四周之后，再看新的优先级是什么
And then four weeks from now, we'll see what the new priorities are.
我觉得 Codex 真正影响这一切的方式主要是
I think that the way that Codex really influences a lot of this stuff is basically,
一是我们几乎可以即时地把东西做出来
one is we can just build things pretty, pretty much instantly.
所以很多时候，我其实会说我们花很多时间去看方案
And so oftentimes, I'd actually say that we spend a lot of time looking at solutions,
决定到底要不要真的把它上线
deciding if we want to actually ship it.
我觉得很多工作是这样的，比如会有一个想法
Um, I think that a lot of the work, you know, there will be an idea, for example, uh,
其实 in-app browser 就是一个很好的例子
the actually the in app browser is a really good example of this
就是我们几个月前加的那个功能
that we added uh a couple months ago.
是我们团队的一个工程师 Ed Fraser 做的，他很厉害
Um, which one of the engineers on our team, Ed Fraser. He's awesome.
基本上是有一天早上，我来上班，他说，你看
He basically, one morning he, I show up to work and he's, look,
我在里面做了个 browser，因为做前端迭代真的很烦
I built the browser in this because it was really annoying doing front end iteration.
你觉得怎么样？我当时就说，太棒了
Uh, what do you think? And I was like, that's awesome.
我们绝对得想办法把它上线
We should definitely figure out how to ship this.
所以那几乎就成了一个起点，有一个真实的产品内分支
And so then that was almost a starting point was having an actual in product branch
我们可以在上面继续开发
that we could actually develop off of.
我觉得这是一个很好的思维模型，就是
And I think that's a good kind of mental model is there's just a lot,
产品开发生命周期在很多方面被反过来了
it's like the product development life cycle is kind of inverted in a lot of ways
因为以前是先花大量前期时间做规划
because before it was very much spend all this upfront time planning
确保工程师只
and really making sure that engineers are only.
去做最重要的事情
Doing the most important things.
而现在其实反过来了，变成先什么都做
And now it's actually flipped and it's a do everything
然后再去搞清楚哪些真的该保留、以什么方式保留
and then let's figure out what actually should go through and in what ways it should.
明白了。这对我们这个职业来说其实真的很了不起
Got it. That's actually really amazing for our profession.
我猜是因为，你基本上是说工程师已经把
I guess because, because you're saying basically like the engineer basically built
MVP 做出来了，他可以在内部完成那个迭代循环，比如给
the MVP already and he can gain that iteration loop internally of like giving
反馈、把它做得更好，直接在真实产品上工作
feedback and make it better and just like working on the actual product
而不是在什么文档上
instead of like some document.
完全正确。总体上，我会说我们尽量让工作
Right totally. And in general, I would say we try to have work, you know,
OpenAI 里每个人都极度相信 AGI
everyone within OpenAI is extremely AGI pill
而且都站在前沿，带着好奇心去思考
and very much at the frontier of thinking about curiously,
我们怎么更好地利用 AI？怎么用这种方式改进产品
how can we leverage AI better? How can we improve our products in this way,
而且我们的工程师都非常有产品思维
but also our engineers are someone that is very product minded,
我觉得这在用 AI 的时候其实真的很重要
and so which I think is actually really important with AI,
用像 Codex 这样的工具时，因为
with tools like Codex because, uh.
人与人之间的协作会变成一个很大的瓶颈
Human to human collaboration becomes a big bottleneck.
如果你看我们的每个项目
If you think about each of our projects,
其实就只有一两个工程师在做，而它们是完整的产品线
we really are just have one or two engineers working on it and it's entire, you know, product lines.
所以在那种有很多工程师的模式下，其实会有大量人力
And so in a mode where there's so many engineers, there's actually a ton of human,
协作开销，而且你推进得也更慢
uh, you know, collaboration overhead, but then also you're moving slower.
于是产品决策可能一周才发生几次
And so then the, the product decisions might happen a couple times over a week
而当一个工程师可以推进得极快时
versus when an engineer can move extremely quickly.
有大量的小决策，理想情况下他们自己就能做
There's a ton of micro decisions that ideally they could just make themselves
而不需要来找我。所以我们启动一个项目的时候，往往
and not need to work with me. And so often when we start, when we start a project, we really,
我想做的就是理清最重要的那些问题
what I try to do is just think through what are the most important questions
也就是我们要为这件事做出哪些关键决策，才能让它
that need kind of decisions that we need to make about this thing to feel it's
与我们整体战略一致并取得成功。所有这些
cohesive to our overall strategy is successful. All of this stuff,
几乎就是我们所做事情的
almost the guardrails of what?
护栏。但除此之外
We're doing. But then beyond that,
我觉得我们的工程师和设计师都相当自主，产品更多是
I think our engineers and our designers move pretty autonomously and product is more, uh,
处于流程的两端，一头是把它推向市场
kind of what the other, that the two ends of the process taking it to market
另一头是前期更偏战略的规划
but also kind of the more strategic planning up front.
明白了。你基本上是想跟踪工程师们
Got it. You're just kind of trying to keep track of like all the stuff the engineers
在做的所有事情，对吧？差不多。说实话
are working on, right? Kind of. Yeah. I mean, honestly,
根本没办法全部跟踪
there's no way to keep track of all of it.
Codex 是我唯一的办法
Codex is my only way.
每天大概都会有个我听到的术语
Every day there's probably something, a term I hear,
这就是我使用 Codex 的方式之一
and this is one of the ways I use Codex,
就是每当我在开会，或者任何时候我不理解某样东西
which is whenever I'm in meetings or literally anytime I don't understand something
或者听到某个我不知道的东西
or I hear something I didn't know about,
我就让 Codex 去收集所有上下文。我得说，一天
I just have Codex go and gather all the context. I would say a couple.
有那么几次，会有人在做某件事，让我觉得
Times a day there's like something that someone's doing where I'm,
他们在做这个太厉害了
it's incredible that they're doing it.
我完全不知道这事在发生。那真是太棒了，兄弟
I had no idea it was happening. And that's amazing that, that's amazing, dude.
所以是的，这真的反过来了，对吧？
So, so yeah, it really has flipped, right?
不再是 PM 试图想出所有点子
It's not it's not like the PM is like trying to come up with all the ideas.
而是恰恰相反，你懂的，不，我是说
It's like the opposite, you know, it's, it's no, I mean,
我是说我们太幸运了。Cursor 也是这样
and I mean we're super lucky. I mean this was also true with Cursor.
显然，从根本上说，我们是在为自己打造工具
Obviously, we're building a tool for ourselves, you know, fundamentally.
挺有意思的，因为
It's funny because.
在 OpenAI 办公室里，你从 A 点走到 B 点，不可能听不到有人提到 Codex
You cannot walk from point a to point B in the OpenAI office without hearing Codex
有人对别人说，或者对我说
get mentioned and someone talk to someone else me go,
我让 Codex 做了这个，或者我真的觉得
I asked Codex to do this or I really think that
如果现在 Codex 宕机了，或者我们没法用它
if Codex went down or we didn't have access to it at this point,
我们公司会…会挺难熬的
our company would be, be operating. It would be, it would be. A pretty tough time.
我想，这本来就是我们最初打造它的原因
And I think, I think that that was originally why we built it in the first place is,
嘿，我们想用它来，你懂的
hey, we want to use it to, you know,
几年前我们启动 Codex 这个项目，是为了加速我们自己的研究
years ago we started Codex as this project to accelerate our own research.
呃，现在事实证明它能帮我们加速一切
Um, now, I mean it turns out that that can just help us accelerate everything.
呃，所以我们就能，你懂的
Um, and so then we can, you know,
我们对它该怎么运作、哪里该更好有直觉
we have the intuition over how it should work and what should be better about it?
本期节目由 Oceans 赞助
This episode is brought to you by oceans.
几个月前我通过 Oceans 招了一个人做播客后期
I hired someone through oceans for podcast post production a few months back
现在很难想象没有他的帮助怎么做这档播客
and can imagine running the podcast without his help.
他很主动，学新工具很快，还用 AI 把他交付的一切叠加放大
He's proactive, picks up new tools fast and uses AI to compound everything that he ships.
Oceans 不只是提供助理，他们提供的是操盘手
Oceans doesn't just place assistants, they place operators.
这些人才精通 AI，交付的产出
The talent is AI fluent and delivers the same output
和资深美国雇员相当，成本却低 3 到 5 倍
as a senior US hire at 3 to 5 x less cost.
他们拒掉 99% 的申请者。所以进到你团队的人
They reject 99% of applicants. So the person who lands on your team is already
从第一天就能上手。如果你在扩张，需要市场、运营
operating from day one. If you're scaling and need marketing, ops,
财务或行政助理方面的帮助
finance or EA help,
我强烈推荐试试 Oceans
I highly recommend giving oceans a try.
去 oceanstalent.com/Peter 看看吧。现在回到我们的节目
Check it out at oceans talent dot com slash Peter. Now back to our episode.
我想在那里工作一定很棒，因为，呃
I imagine must be incredible working there because, um,
这是个挺有意思的处境，因为，是的
it's kind of an interesting spot because like, yeah,
我已经完全转向 Codex，几乎任何你想自动化或
I switched completely to Codex and like pretty much anything you want to automate or
简化的东西，你都可以直接让 Codex 去搞定
streamline, you can just ask Codex to figure it out
然后围绕它构建一个 skill 之类的，对吧？与此同时，我
and like build a skill or something around around it, right? At the same time, I.
感觉 OpenAI 大概有，什么，10 亿 ChatGPT 用户
Feel like OpenAI has like what like like 1 billion ChatGPT users.
那你要怎么让普通用户，你懂的
So how do you get the normies to, you know,
爱上 Codex，又不至于让他们不知所措呢？
get Codex pilled without overwhelming them like that?
这算是关键问题，对吧？
That's, that's kind of like the key, the key problem, right?
所以，是的，我是说，这真的很有意思，因为我觉得
So it's like, yeah, yeah, I mean, it's, it's really interesting because I think,
我是说，我在 AI 编程领域做了一段时间了，现在感觉是
I mean, I've worked in AI coding for a while and now it's like,
事实证明这些 agent 对每个人都超级有用
turns out these agents are super useful for everybody.
但我觉得连开发者都还没完全适应你可以对
Um, but I think developers even haven't fully warmed up to the level of ambition you
Codex 抱有多大的期待
can have with Codex.
你知道，如果你走进任何一家大企业，可能顶尖的 5% 到 10%
Um, you know, if you go within to any large enterprise, maybe at the top 5 to 10%,
最接受 AI 的前沿工程师正在最大化利用 Codex
most kind of AI pills, frontier engineers are maximally leveraging Codex,
但还有一大批人仍然停留在，你懂的
but then there's a long tail of people that are still. You know,
也许还在结对编程，很少做委派之类的
maybe pair programming, doing less delegation, things that,
但有意思的是，工程师在过去三年里见证了 AI
but it's interesting because engineers have kind of seen AI incrementally expand its
逐步扩展自己的能力
capabilities over the last three years.
但如果你看非开发者，这一路以来基本就只有 ChatGPT
But then if you look to a non developer it's kind of been just ChatGPT this whole time.
所以他们问 ChatGPT 的那类东西，跟你实际上
And so then the type of things that they're asking chat are very different than what
能委派给 Codex 的东西非常不同。是的
you can actually delegate to Codex. Yeah.
所以说实话，我觉得这对我们是个大机会，就是搞清楚
And so honestly, I think that is the big opportunity for us is to figure out, um,
有哪些方法能让人们对自己能提出的要求更有野心？
you know, what are the ways to just make people feel more ambitious with what they can ask?
因为归根结底，其实几乎没有什么
Uh, because ultimately I was, it's, there's actually nothing,
你在工作上需要做的几乎所有事，几乎都应该
almost everything you should, you need to do professionally should almost always
立刻让 Codex 开始去做
just immediately have Codex start doing it.
所以我觉得这既是一个有意思的产品问题
So I think that, that is an interesting kind of both product
也是一种整体上的赋能问题
and kind of enablement overall.
就是一种心态上的挑战。是的
Just, uh, mentality challenge. Yeah,
随着时间推移，我对它提的要求越来越大胆了
I've gotten more ambitious with my requests for it over time.
比如我有个 skill，它能一次性发到大概 7 个社交媒体平台
Like I have a skill that, you know, it posts like 7 social media platforms at once
而且其中一堆平台根本没有 API
and a bunch of them don't even have API.
所以我就直接用浏览器来搞定。对，用浏览器
So I just use like the browser used to totally. No, the browser.
我觉得特别酷的一点是，我们采取的思路很大程度上就是
And that's what I think is so cool is the approach we've taken very much has been
为 Codex 打造这些非常有用的基础能力，让它能和你的电脑交互
build these really useful primitives for Codex to interact with your computer.
然后神奇的地方在于，当它们全部组合成一个整体时
And then the magic is when they all kind of combined into this thing
你甚至都不知道、也根本不需要知道任何东西是怎么运作的
where you don't even know, you don't even need to know how anything works.
你要做的只是把你的需求告诉 Codex
All you do is just ask Codex for what you need.
而在底层，Codex 其实知道怎么调用自己，去真正完成
And under the hood, Codex actually knows how to use itself to then actually do the
你需要的事，对吧？所以我用 browser use 最神奇的体验，并不是
things you need, right? So the most magical experiences I've had with browser use are not
我让它用浏览器、或者让它用我电脑的时候
when I ask it to use browser or ask it to use my computer.
而是当它自己在尝试做某件事的时候。有一次，我做了
It's just when it was trying to do something. Once I was, I built,
我写了一个 Notion doc
I wrote a Notion doc
我基本上想根据这个 Notion doc 创建一个 Site，来做个
and I basically wanted to create a site off of the Notion doc to kind of, you know,
原型之类的。于是我问 Codex，你能把这个 Notion doc 变成一个 Site 吗？
prototype something. And so I asked Codex, can you turn this Notion doc into a site?
Sites 就是我们最近推出的那种托管网页，然后它
Um, which sites is kind of the, the hosted websites we, we launched recently and it,
有意思的是，它做完之后，我
it was funny because then I went it, it did it and then I,
我回去看了它的执行记录
I went back and looked at the trace
结果基本上是 Notion MCP 没有暴露获取文档里实际图片的功能
and it basically notion MCP didn't expose getting the actual images in the DOC.
于是 Codex 打开了一个浏览器，直接进到 DOM 里
And so Codex opened up a browser and then just went into the Dom
拿到了真正的文件图片，然后把它用在网站里
and got the actual file image and then use that in the website.
我当时就想，太厉害了。我很高兴它这么做了
And I was like, that's amazing. I'm glad it did that.
所以这类事情对我来说真的很神奇
So it's kind of that type of stuff feels really magical to me.
是啊，兄弟，某种程度上它比人还有人味
Yeah, dude, it's like, it's a lot more person than humans in some ways.
它就是会一直努力去搞明白。完全同意。我觉得这
It just keeps trying to figure it out. So totally. And I think that's,
有意思的是，我觉得这就是为什么我们的 goal 功能
and it's funny like, I mean, I think that's why our goal features, you know,
感觉非常有用，因为总体上
feels really useful because there is generally the,
我们在 OpenAI 和 Codex 上
our goal with OpenAI and with Codex
以及在我们的 agent 上的目标，就是希望它不断地更擅长完成
and generally with our agents is we want it to just keep getting better at doing
越来越难、越来越有野心、时间跨度越来越长的高难度任务。而且往往
harder and harder, more ambitious, longer, hard time horizon tasks. Um, and often.
其中一部分是在 harness 层面，但也有一部分只是在于范围
Some of that's like the harness level, but some of that's also just at the scope of,
就是在有 goal 功能之前得不断给它下 prompt
you know, continuing to prompt it before we had goal.
我觉得人们通常做的就是加一堆引导，比如说好
I think often what people would do is just add a bunch of steers where it's okay,
继续、然后继续、然后再继续。对对
keep going and then keep going and then keep going. Yeah, yeah.
但我觉得现在，它就会
But I think now it's, you know, it'll just,
它现在会一直做下去，直到真正满足条件为止
it'll just keep going now until it actually meets the criteria,
我觉得这太棒了
which I think is awesome.
明白了。我记得你给我们准备了几个 demo
Got it. I think you prepare like a few demos for us.
你想分享一些 PM 的工作流吗？
Do you want to kind of share some PM workflows?
好，我会在一个演示环境里分享，因为我们没法直接展示
Yeah, I'm gonna share kind of in a dummy environment cause we're not able to share
我在 OpenAI 里做的东西
the things I'm doing in OpenAI directly,
但希望能借此说明其中一些做法
but it'll hopefully be able to illustrate some of this stuff.
有几种不同的方式，我是说
So there's a few different ways that, I mean,
我用 Codex 做很多不同的事
there's a lot of different things that I do with Codex.
先给大家做个介绍，这是 Codex app
I think one thing actually, and so just to orient everyone, this is the Codex app.
呃，这算是一个 agent 开发环境
Um, this is kind of you know an an agent development environment
我们构建的，有点像 agent 控制面板
that we've built it's kind of an agent control plane.
呃，它能做很多事。最基础的是
Um, and so there's a lot of different things. The most fundamental thing is,
你可以发起一个 chat
you know, you can start a chat.
呃，模型这些东西，可以在一个项目里运行，也可以独立运行
Um, the model, all this stuff, it can work within a 5A project or just on its own.
但呃，我用 Codex 有几种不同的方式
But, um, so there's a few different ways that I use Codex
对我来说非常有价值
that are really valuable to me.
一个是在 OpenAI，我们有大量的聊天
So one is that at OpenAI, you know, we have a ton of chat,
我们非常重度地使用 Slack，所以有大量 Slack channel
we use Slack very heavily and so we have a ton of Slack channels
从客户那里获取反馈
that we get feedback from customers,
内部团队也发反馈、讨论想法。所以我做的一件事——
our internal teams send feedback that we discuss ideas. And so one of the things I.
我用 Codex 做的，其实就是整合反馈
Use Codex for is actually to just synthesize feedback,
把重要的东西标出来
kind of highlight important things
然后上传到一个 Linear board 里，方便我之后 review
and then actually upload it into a linear board that I can review later.
这大致展示了我的做法
And so this is kind of illustrative of what I did,
本质上就是我在 Codex 里写了一个 thread
which is essentially there's a thread that I wrote in Codex
让它去整合反馈
where I asked it for feedback.
我其实也花了很多时间让它搞清楚怎么
I actually, you know, also spent a lot of time asking it to figure out how to
正确地把内容录入 Linear，以及哪些方式比较合理
correctly input it into linear and what are the ways that make sense.
然后通常，这一点对很多其他工作流也成立
And then often, and this is very true for a lot of other workflows,
我会直接让 Codex 设置一个自动化，持续做这件事
I'll then just ask Codex to set up an automation to do this continuously.
呃，很棒的一点是 Codex 其实知道怎么设置它自己的自动化
Um, and so what's great is Codex actually knows how to set up its own automations.
所以 Codex 能够进去说，好
And so Codex was actually able to go in and say, great,
现在每天做一次，或者每周做一次
now do this every day or do this every week.
然后，我常做的一件事就是说
And then, you know, things that I would often also do is say, you know,
每次做完也给我发一条 Slack 消息，然后 Codex 就能进去
also send a Slack message to me every time it finishes and then Codex can go in
更新这个自动化
and update the automation.
所以我大概设置了五六个不同的自动化
And so there's probably five or six different automations list that I've set up
原本是个手动流程，我先让 Codex 做一遍
where it's a manual process that I then ask Codex to do once
然后就让它去把自动化设置好
and then I just ask it to, you know, go and set up the automation.
我会说这对很多事情来说是个巨大的解锁
And so this is probably a big, I would say this is a huge unlock for a lot of things.
而且还有一些很有意思的创造性方式来用自动化
And there's also really interesting creative ways that you can use automation.
我经常做的一件事，基本上就是告诉 Codex
Something that I'll do often is, you know, basically tell Codex.
就是有某条消息发出去了，或者——
You know, there's some, there was some sort of message that got sent or.
比如我发了一条消息，然后根据那条消息的结果
Well, I'll have sent a message and then based on the results of that message,
我会去问我的一个同事一个问题
I'll ask a question to one of my co-workers.
所以我会说，嘿，当 Alex 回复这条消息时，请
So I'll be like, hey, when Alex responds to this message, please,
或者回复我发给他的最后一条私信时，呃，给客户发一封回复邮件
or to the last DM I sent him, um, drop a response email to the client.
呃，基本上 Codex 会做的就是在底层用自动化
Um, and, you know, so basically what Codex will do is actually use automations under
来不断检查，呃
the hood to kind of keep checking, uh,
我和 Alex 的那条 Slack 消息，然后一旦触发
the Slack message that I had with Alex and then essentially once it triggers.
它就会草拟一封邮件，然后把这个自动化删掉
It'll draft an email and then actually delete the automation.
我觉得真正酷的地方是，用 Codex——
And so I think that the things that's really cool is using code.
Codex 知道怎么用它自己
Codex knows how to use itself.
呃，所以你可以让它做几乎任何随意的事
Um, and so you can just ask it to do pretty much random things
哪怕没说得很具体，它也会用自己的原语把
that aren't very specified, and it'll just use its own primitives to do
那件事做得很好。哦，哦，这有意思。好
that really well. Oh, oh, that's interesting. Okay.
是啊，我以前设置过每日任务和每周任务
Yeah, I've, I've set up like daily jobs and weekly jobs before
但没做过这种触发的东西，比如就等 Alex 回复
but not this kind of trigger stuff like just like Alex responding
然后触发某件事
and trigger something.
所以，所以它真的会去做
So. So it'll actually like it'll actually do it
而且事后真的会把它删掉
and they'll actually remove it afterwards.
没错。因为它可以更新自动化，它会——
Exactly. Because it can update the automation can have, it'll,
它会设置自动化，让它在满足验收标准时自己删掉这个自动化
it'll set up the automation to actually tell itself to delete the automation when it,
当它满足验收标准的时候
it, it meets the acceptance criteria.
嗯，所以你基本上可以做任何
Um, and so you can do really, it basically anything
基于时间或者需要某种触发的事情
that's time based or requires kind of a trigger.
实际上 Codex 会设置自动化来做这些事
You can actually, Codex will set up automations to do those things
而且你都不需要说得特别具体，嗯，这挺酷的
and you don't even need to kind of be very specific. Um, which is cool.
嗯，老兄。所以你可以做一个自动化，比如
Um, dude. So you can, you can, you can do like an automation where like
如果有人在 Slack 的长 thread 里 tag Rohan，就假装是 Rohan 来回复
if someone tags Rohan in Slack on long thread, just like pretend to be Rohan respond.
没错。是的。其实挺好玩的，Alex 也是
Exactly. Yeah. So actually it's funny, Alex also,
他刚跟我们几个分享过，他会打 @Codex
he was just sharing this with a couple of us where he'll like do at Codex.
但它并不是一个 Slack 应用
But it's not a Slack app.
它只是一个每隔几分钟运行一次的自动化，看看他有没有 tag Codex
It'll just be an automation running every few minutes to see if he tagged Codex
然后它就会直接回复
and then it'll actually just respond.
我是说，有很多，是的，我觉得自动化说实话有点
I mean, there's a lot of, yeah, I think automations are honestly kind of an,
不是不被重视，而是有点没被充分利用，我觉得
not under appreciated, but kind of under leveraged, I think,
这是我们一个很灵活的功能，因为
feature that we have because it's so flexible because of the fact
Codex 可以智能地去更新它
that Codex can intelligently kind of update it.
所以，是的，这一点，抱歉。哦，很快很快说一下
But so, yeah, this one thing or sorry. Oh, real, real, real quick.
我对自动化的一个问题是，嗯，很多都是本地运行的，对吧？
My, my one problem with automations is like, um, like a lot of them are local, right?
所以它们只在电脑开着的时候运行
So they only run when the computers on.
所以有时候如果我设了个周五早上的任务，而我电脑没开
So some, sometimes if I do like a Friday morning thing and my computer is not on it,
它就不会运行，你懂的，完全不行
it doesn't work, you know, totally so.
所以我猜我得把它放到 Mac mini 之类的上面，对吧？
So I guess I have to put it on my Mac mini or something, right?
是的，那是一个选择。我是说，我们确实推出了移动端支持
Yeah, that is one option. I mean, we did launch, uh, mobile, support for mobile.
嗯，你也可以在云端控制远程的 Codex 实例
Um, and kind of in, you can also control remote, uh, instances of Codex via in, in the cloud.
是的，不过我们打算，目前我们还没有原生的云端自动化
Yeah, but we are going to, so right now we don't have native cloud automations,
但这是在规划中的东西。所以，我觉得它
but that is something that, you know, is in the pipeline. So, but I think it's,
挺有意思的，因为我知道有个梗，就是笔记本电脑
it's kind of interesting because I know there's a meme of the laptop kind of,
你知道的，稍微开着一条缝
you know, slightly ajar.
但说实话，我刚加入的时候，我有点，哦，你知道
But I mean, to be honest, I originally, when I joined, I was kind of, oh, you know,
觉得自动化只能本地运行有点局限
the automations being local feels limiting.
但我觉得如果你只是这么用它们，我是说
But I think that in the if you kind of are just using them, I mean,
大部分时候，我一整天笔记本都是开着的
for the most part, my whole day my laptop's open.
所以其实这没成什么大问题，但我确实觉得，你知道
So it's, it actually hasn't been a huge problem, but I do think it's, you know,
我们肯定会在那方面提供一些解决方案。那么另外
we are going to have some solutions there for sure. So the other,
另一件我觉得非常有意思的事
the other thing that I think is really interesting
我觉得它真正从根本上改变了我们的工作方式
that I think is has really fundamentally changed the way that we work,
或者至少是我的工作方式，那就是 Image Gen
or at least the way that I work, is image gen.
你其实可以直接在 Codex 里用 Image Gen，只要你 tag Image Gen
So you can actually use image gen directly in Codex if you just tag image gen,
也就是那个 skill，它就会触发去调用这个模型
the skill, it'll actually trigger using the model.
所以这真的很有意思，因为我觉得这
And so it's, it's really interesting because I think this is
如果你想想我们原本是怎么考虑用 AI 来做快速
if you think about the way that we were thinking about using AI to kind of do quick
设计迭代的，往往是写代码来做原型
design iterations, it often was writing code to prototype things.
但我其实觉得 Image Gen 是一种快得多的做想法原型的方式
But I actually think image Gen is a much faster way to prototype ideas.
所以这，我举个例子说明一下。我截了一张图，你知道的
And so this is, and just illustrate the example. So I took a screenshot of, you know, the,
就是你可以在 Codex 里输入新消息的那个输入框，然后我基本上说
the composer where you can type in a new message into Codex and I basically said,
嘿，你知道，当你启动 Codex 时，你可以在那里选择项目
hey, you know, when you, when you launch Codex, there you can select the project.
于是我让 Image Gen，或者说让 Codex 用 Image Gen，做出四五个
And so I asked image gen or X Codex using image Gen to basically prototype 4 or five
改进选择项目方式的想法原型
ideas to improve the way to select the project.
嗯，它确实生成了一堆不同的想法，嗯
Um, and so that did is actually, you know, generated a bunch of different ideas, um,
你知道，一下子就很不错。我觉得，我是说，对我来说，它其实
you know, nice immediately. And I think what's, I mean, to me, it actually,
这对我来说算是一个 AGI 时刻，因为我
this was kind of an AGI moment for me where I was,
因为我觉得我们一直把 Image Gen 当成一个用来做
cause I think we always think of image gen as this thing which is useful for making,
我也说不好，把我的头发变蓝之类的东西
I don't know, turn my hair blue or something.
嗯，但它其实能做出这么好的数字化 mock
Um, but the fact that it can create such good digital mocks, essentially, um,
真的让超快速的迭代成为可能，对吧？
really allows for super quick iteration, right?
对我来说这感觉是快得多的迭代
This feels like much quicker iteration to me,
比生成 5 个不同的 React 假网站的迭代要快得多
iteration than kind of generating 5 different react dummy websites.
嗯，然后我经常会说，你知道，酷，这太棒了
Um, and then what I'll often do is say, you know, cool, that was awesome.
现在拿第一个，把它做成一个原型，在一个，嗯
Now take the first one and make a prototype of it on a, um.
生成到 Site 上，于是它创建出来的东西就可以被分享
On a site. And so then, then something that it creates something that can be shared, um,
然后我们就能基于它来思考
and then, you know, we can kind of reason over it.
所以我会说，Image Gen 绝对为做原型带来了巨大的突破
So I'd say image gen was definitely been a huge unlock for prototyping, um,
也让表达想法变得更容易
and just generally expressing ideas
在产品里，你是直接给它一张参考截图，还是必须
and in product like do you just give it a reference screenshot or do you have to
给它某种设计系统之类的东西？不
give it some sort of like design system thing or? No,
就只是一张参考截图
just just a reference screenshot.
对，这一个就是只给了截图，它就能
Yeah, for this one, I mean, so just gave the screenshot and it was able,
它能够很好地保持在设计语言之内
it's able to, you know, do a pretty good job of staying within the design language.
我们在 OpenAI 内部也做了一些 skill，基本上
Um, we've also built skills internally at OpenAI that basically, uh,
会强制执行我们的设计语言
kind of enforce our ref, our, our design language, um,
或者说让 Codex 能够访问它
when then or it enables Codex to kind of access it
在它生成设计素材的时候
when it is generating design assets.
另一个有意思的点是，你可以用插件来集成
Um, the other thing that's interesting is you can integrate with into, with plugins,
比如 Figma 插件
the Figma plugin.
对，这样它就能把 design tokens 之类的东西拉进来
Um, yeah, and so then that'll actually be able to pull things here to design tokens
诸如此类的，不过对观众来说，就用一个很基础的
and things like that but like for for the audience just just like a really basic
skill，比如告诉它这是配色、这是字体，还有
scale is just like here's the colors. Here's the fonts and here's like, you know,
差不多就这些，对吧？就是这类东西
that's it, right? Like that, that kind of stuff.
我想说，这些东西最棒的地方在于
And I mean what's great with things, you know,
经常会出现这种情况：你做了一轮迭代，看着它然后说
an often thing might happen is you do this iteration, you look at this and you say,
嘿，这不对，不完全是我想要的。于是你就一直调，直到对为止
hey, this wasn't right, quite what I wanted. And so you keep saying it until it is.
然后你能做的是，我们有个叫 skill creator 的东西
And then what you can do is actually use, we have something called a skill creator,
它其实能创建 skill，你可以说，嘿 Codex
uh, which is actually able to create skills and what you can say is hey Codex,
看看这个 thread，创建一个 skill，确保你以后保持一致
look at this thread and create a skill to ensure you are consistent moving forward.
我会说这是我们很常做的一件事，就是你
Um, and this is, I'd say a. Pretty common thing that we do, which is, uh, you,
你和 Codex 有某种交互，然后你就让 Codex
you have some sort of interaction with Codex and you just tell Codex to kind of,
在元层面上做点什么，做一个 skill
at the metal level, do something, make a skill,
做一个插件，确保这件事以后基本上被模板化
make a plugin to ensure that this thing gets essentially templatized moving forward.
对，我也是这么做的。就像是，我，你知道
Yeah, that that's why I do too. It's like, so like I, you know,
我有做各种事情的 skill，然后它有时候没法一次
I have skills for doing stuff and then like it doesn't quite get it right in one
就做对。所以我得给它反馈，我会说，嘿
shot some sometimes. So I have to give it feedback and I'm like, hey,
你能更新一下 skill，把这个反馈考虑进去吗？
can you update the skill to account for this feedback?
但是兄弟，我担心的一件事是，就像
But but like dude 1 one thing I worry about is, is like,
因为我其实不会去看它做的那些更新，所以我担心
cause I don't actually read the updates that it makes so that I'm worried
我会把这个 skill 搞得越来越烂。就是说，如果我一直让它干活
that I'll just like slopify the skill. Like, you know, if I keep making it do stuff.
你也担心这个吗，还是你有别的办法
Do you worry about that, too, or do you have a.
对，我确实会想这个，因为我觉得很多时候，我是说
Yeah, no, I do think about that because I feel a lot of times, um, I mean,
这算是我们在思考的一个普遍问题
and this is kind of a general, uh, thing that we're kind of thinking about,
就是很多东西。Skill
which is a lot of things. Skills
和插件确实会往 prompt 里加进很多东西
and plugins do introduce a lot of in things to the prompt.
所以我们开始思考
And so we're starting to think about, you know,
尤其是当你有更多自主 agent 在运行时
especially as you have more autonomous agents running,
有没有办法在你改动之后对输出做评估，或者说
are there ways to kind of eval the output when you make changes to it or, you know,
建立信心？现在我的做法就是测试一下，基本上，行，看起来不错
build confidence? Right now what I'll do is I'll just test it and basically, cool, looks good.
然后就继续往下走
And kind of keep going.
好的，酷
Okay, cool.
我要分享的最后一件我做的事情
The last thing that I'll share on the just things that I do
我觉得非常高杠杆的是
that I think are super leveraged is.
本质上，很多时候，这有点关联到那种一次性软件的想法
Essentially, oftentimes. And this kind of goes to this idea of kind of disposable software.
创建软件和工具变得太容易了
It's so easy to create software and tools.
所以用 Codex，我经常就做一些一次性的东西
And so using Codex and so often I'll just create one off things
不见得可复现。但举个例子，我们用得很多
that aren't necessarily reproducible. But for example, you know, we use a lot and
经常会有一大堆消息需要我回复
so often there'll be just a ton of messages that I need to respond to.
所以我会当场让 Codex 给我生成一些小应用
And so I'll actually just on the fly ask Codex to generate little apps for me to
来处理其他工具里正在发生的事情
work through things that are happening in other tools.
比如说，我常干的一件事是，嘿，看看我所有的 Slack 消息
Um, so for example, a common thing I'll be is, hey, look at all my Slack messages,
找出最重要的、需要回复的那些
uh, figure out the most important ones to respond to
然后在一个本地网页里以可视化的方式展示给我
and then actually just show it to me visually within a local website.
于是它就会生成不同版本的东西
Um, and so then it'll kind of generate, you know, different versions of things.
嗯，我其实还设置了一个功能：当它生成了某些东西
This, um, something I actually have set up also is when it generates something
感觉挺有用，比如「哦，这个我可以反复用」
that feels useful, oh, I can actually use this repeatedly,
那我就会设置一个自动化，让它去更新这个，嗯，每隔
then I'll actually just set up an automation to tell it to update this, um, every,
比如说一小时。这样我就可以直接在这个基础上工作
let's say, hour. And so then I can actually just work out of this a little bit.
嗯，所以我觉得有很多
Um, so I think that there's a lot of,
我会说，这里有很多尚未被充分利用的
and I'd say this is where there's a lot of overhang of, uh,
能力，因为我们习惯了这样看待软件
capabilities where I think we're used to thinking about software,
觉得这些小应用要花很多力气去做
these little apps taking a lot of effort.
嗯，但现在这么简单
Um, and but then now it's so easy.
所以你其实可以为你需要的一切
So then you can actually just create extremely custom versions of everything
创建极度定制化的版本，做出适合你的工作流
that you need for, like, the workflows that make sense for you.
嗯，明白了。所以这个是关于，呃
Um, got it. So this one is about like, uh,
有点像一份按优先级排好的清单，列出你需要
kind of like a prioritized list of things you need to
回复的事情或要采取的行动。对
respond to or actions you have to take. Yeah.
我经常做的另一个版本是，看过去一天的消息
Another version of this that I'll often do is look at the last day of messages
找出我做过的所有承诺，嗯
and find all the commitments that I made, um,
然后给我一份按优先级排好的清单
and then kind of give me a prioritized list of that.
所以，呃，你知道，我觉得，我得说我不是那种最
And so, uh, you know, I think that, you know, I would say I'm not the most, uh,
有条理的人，但我觉得有了 Codex，它让我基本上可以
organized person in general, but I think with Codex it enables me to just basically
把整理和跟进都交给这个工具，因为它做得到
delegate organization and persistence to the tool because it can.
关于这个，我其实前不久还发过推特，大概是说
And this, I actually, I think I just tweeted about this where it's like,
有那么多事情要做，嗯
there's so many things where you have so much to do, um,
待办清单经常越堆越多，你就会有种感觉
and often it just the to do list adds up and you kind of feel.
你知道，会有些焦虑
You know, there's some anxiety there.
我觉得真正让人轻松的是，你可以直接让 Codex 去做这些
And I think what's really relieving is actually you can just ask Codex to do these
事情，最终大概有 80% 的情况下
things and ultimately have, probably 80% of the time,
它真的会把你要做的那件事从清单上勾掉
it'll actually just knock the thing off the list that you needed to do.
嗯，所以对我来说，你知道
Um, and so for me that's, you know,
这基本上腾出了大量的心理空间，让我能专注于更重要的事
basically frees up a ton of mental space to be able to focus on more important things.
对，我感觉几乎所有这些工作流
Yeah, I feel like almost all these work streams,
包括战略之类的一切，机器都能做掉大概 80%
including like strategy and everything is like the the machine can do like 80% of it
然后最后 20% 你再加上你自己的润色
and then the last 20% you kind of apply your touch to it.
对，也许随着时间推移，这 20% 会越来越少
Yeah, maybe you'll get fewer and fewer over time.
哦，对，对。呃，我觉得还有，对
Oh, yeah, yeah. Uh, and I think also there's, yeah,
是 80% 的情况，也许有些时候机器能做到十成十
it's 80% of the time and maybe some of the time the machine can do it N10.
但就是，我觉得也有很多时间，尤其是
But it's like, I think also there's so much time where as especially
作为产品经理，我们花在收集上下文上
as product managers where we just spend gathering context.
呃，你被拉进一个 Slack thread，里面有 50 条消息
Uh, you get added to a Slack thread and it has like 50 messages.
你平常得坐在那儿花 15 分钟光是读完它们
You would normally have to sit there and spend 15 minutes just reading them.
我经常做的是，直接进 Slack，复制一个 thread
Often what I'll do is just go into Slack, copy a thread,
然后让 Codex 给我一个简短的 TLDR
and then ask Codex to just give me a little TLDR of this
然后我马上就能回复
and then I can immediately kind of respond.
所以我觉得，你知道，一整天下来
And so I think you just, you know, over the course of the day,
我做的事情大概是没有 Codex 时的三四倍
I'm probably doing 3 or 4 x more than I would have without Codex,
这挺疯狂的
which is pretty crazy.
而且在产品开发流程之外，可能也有一大堆用途
And there's probably a ton of just like outside the product development process.
我发现 AI 在很多地方超级有用，比如面试候选人
I found AI super helpful for like, you know, like interviewing candidates,
比如总结面试记录，或者写我自己的绩效评估
like summarizing interview notes or like writing my own performance review.
你大概可以，因为它有记忆，对吧？
You can probably cause, cause it has mem memory, right?
所以你大概可以直接让它写一份绩效评估。哦，完全可以
So you can probably just get it to like write a performance review. Oh, totally.
对，我真的，因为我也最不擅长把我实际做过的事情
Yeah, I really, cause I'm also worst at actually documenting anything
记录下来
that I've actually done.
嗯，我是说，我职业生涯大部分时间都是创始人
Um, I mean, I've been a founder most of my career,
所以我通常就是埋头做事，通常，呃，但有意思的是
so I usually just do stuff and it's usually, uh, but it's funny because then that's,
对，你可以直接告诉 Codex，去看看我在
yeah, you can just tell Codex, go look at what's all the things I've contributed in
过去三个月里贡献了哪些东西，它就会，你知道
the last three months and it'll, you know.
花几个小时，实实在在整理出一份权威清单。对
Spend a couple hours and really just put together the definitive list. Yeah.
想象一下，开会也变得更有趣了，对吧？
Imagine the meetings are more fun, too, right?
因为很多时间大概都花在，比如
Because probably a lot of it's spent just, like,
搭建原型、实际体验产品上，对吧？这是我的猜测。对。对
putting up prototypes and like playing the actual product, right? That's my guess. Yeah. Yeah.
我是说，尤其是，老实说，很多时候
So I mean, I think, yeah, especially, I mean, honestly, a lot of,
因为我们很多工作也是面对面进行的
because we work in a lot of, we work very in person as well.
所以我们会有很多偶然发生的对话
So there's a lot of just, uh, serendipitous conversations that we have.
就是某个人展示他们做出来的东西，然后你会想，天呐
And that's someone showing the thing that they built and then it's, oh my God,
那我们就从这里往下走一点吧
you know, let's actually a little bit, um, and kind of go from there, dude.
所以，就是那种，你懂的
So, like, um, so like, you know, did.
那你觉得你的日程还是被会议塞满，还是真的有做东西的时间？
So do you think your schedule is filled with meetings still or do you have an actual build time?
嗯，我是说，在 OpenAI
Like, yeah, I mean, I'm so, I mean, at OpenAI,
我很关注的一件事是我们的企业业务
one of the thing I focus a lot on our enterprise motion and
所以，呃，我确实开了相当多的
so okay uh I do spend I mean I do actually probably have a pretty large number of
会，比最理想的情况要多
meetings relative to what would be optimal.
但其中很多其实就是和客户开的
But a lot of that's actually just with customers.
呃，不过我做东西的时间基本是下午五点之后
Um, so, but yeah, I would say my build time is uh from five PM onwards.
晚上的时候。不过，有意思的是
Evening time. But, uh, but no, I think that it's funny
因为我甚至会用 Codex
because actually I'll even use Codex
当我的私人幕僚长
as my personal chief of staff.
所以每周一开始，我会让它看一遍我所有的会议
So in the beginning of the week, I'll have it look at all my meetings, figure out,
把能合并的合并起来
you know, consolidate the ones where it can be more,
给我留出专注时间块，再找出哪些会可以
can give me focus blocks and figure out which ones could be, like.
用一条私信取消掉之类的。所以它确实在帮我找到专注时间
Canceled as a DM or something. So it's definitely helping me find the focus time.
但总体来说，我们空出来的时间其实主要是花更多
But I think in general, what we do in the free time is actually just spend way more
时间陪客户。我是说
time with our customers. I mean, yeah, I, I,
我觉得任何和客户的会都绝对值得开
I think any meeting with customers definitely worth taking.
这点毫无疑问，那我来问几个问题，因为我
So yeah, no doubt about that and let me just ask some questions cause like I,
我也算是变成了 Codex 的重度用户
I kind of become a Codex power user too.
呃，我遇到的一个难题是
Like, uh, one, one thing I struggle with is like, I,
我不知道像 Peter Steinberger 那样的人是怎么做到的，但我
I don't know how people like Peter Steinberger can do it, but like I,
我差不多最多只能同时处理大概 3、4 个 Codex thread
I can pretty much only work on maybe like 3 or 4 Codex threads at the same time.
你在面板上通常同时开着多少个活跃的对话？
You know, like how many active conversations do you have going on the panel?
嗯，我觉得 Peter 绝对是另一个层次
Yeah, I think, I mean, Peter's definitely on another level.
所以我会说，也许别一上来就学他那样
So I would say maybe don't necessarily immediately start that.
别在家轻易尝试。但对我来说，一般大概是
Try that at home. But I think for me, um, I would say I'm like probably, and in general,
五六个 thread。但有意思的是，这非常像在委派任务
five or six kind of threads. But what's interesting is it's not, it's very delegated.
所以我常常不是在干等它。我就把它发出去
So I'm often not waiting for it. It's just, I'll fire it off.
然后一个会结束、或者有空隙的时候，我回到 Codex
And then the end of a meeting or I have a free second, I go back to Codex,
看到所有未读，然后我会发现，哦，其实挺好
I see all the unreads, and I actually then have, oh, actually, that's great.
它确实做好了我要准备的那份幻灯片
It did make the slide deck that I was preparing for,
是给明天某个会用的，然后我就可以在上面继续迭代
for the next some meeting tomorrow and then I can kind of iterate on it.
所以我对这套
So I kind of, it's kind of a, the way that I think about the,
范式的理解更像是，你懂的
the paradigm is much more, you know,
比如说你手下有个你管理的同事
let's say that you have someone that you work with that you manage.
如果他们做的每件事你都得时刻盯着状态
If everything they were doing, you had to maintain constant state on it,
那这就不是很有效的委派了
it wouldn't be a very effective delegation.
呃，我觉得 Codex 的目标就是，我们怎么更多地走向
Um, and I think with Codex, that's the goal is how do we move much more to
那种完全委派的状态，它做完就直接反馈给你
that fully delegated state where it's, it just comes back to you.
它在做的过程中，你不用去操心它在干什么
You didn't have to think about what it was doing while it was doing it.
我觉得这就开始解决那种，呃
And that, I think, kind of starts to address that, uh,
所需要的心智负担问题
just the mental overhead required.
呃，一个很好的例子是，假设你在推进一个功能
Um, and a good example of this is with, let's say you're pushing a feature, uh,
你想把一个 PR 合并上线
you want to get a product, get a PR landed, um,
我们做的一些东西是，你其实可以让 Codex 去照看那个 PR
some of the stuff that we've built is you can actually ask Codex to nurse that PR.
等 CI 跑完，然后修好 CI，继续推进
Wait for the CI to finish, then fix the CI and keep going
并回应 PR 上任何来自人类的反馈
and respond to any human feedback on the PR.
然后一旦它完全准备好了
And then once it's fully ready to go,
就在 Slack 上提醒我，告诉我可以合并了
then ping me on Slack and let me know that I can merge it.
所以以前你得花上 10 个不同的交互点
And so now you would have previously have to spend 10 different interaction points
去操心那个 PR，但现在只在最后，好，酷，看
thinking about that PR, but now it's just at the very end, okay, cool, look,
可以上线了。然后你就可以往下走了
it's good to go. And then you can kind of go.
那你有没有搭出一套系统来管理这套系统，就像大家在
So have you managed to build a system to manage the system like people talk about
Twitter 上聊的 loop 之类的东西。你是不是也在往那个方向发展？
loops and stuff on Twitter. Have you, are you kind of trending that direction too?
或者？或者说？嗯，说实话，我还没到那步
Or? Or like? Yeah, I think honestly, I haven't.
抱歉，我觉得，是的，还没到
I'm sorry. I feel like, yeah, not at the, the,
Peter 说的那个更高级的层次
the next level that Peter is talking about,
但我现在还停留在手动写 prompt 的阶段
but it's so I'm still out here prompting.
我觉得，但对我来说，说实话我会说 slash
I think the, but the thing that for me I think I mean honestly I would say uh slash
goal 是这方面一个不错的版本，它会自己不断迭代
goal is a good version of this where it'll just keep iterating on itself.
嗯，我更想优化的其实是，基本上
Um, the thing that I'm trying to optimize more for is basically, basically the, the,
我现在整体的优化逻辑是，每次我做任何事时
the general optimization function for me right now is every time I do anything,
我基本都会想，这件事 Codex 能不能做？
I basically think, could Codex have done this?
然后还有一整类
And then there's, but then there's a whole class of,
那是一整类的事情
so that's the whole class of things.
然后还有另外一整类事情
Then there's a whole separate class of things that are things
是我们今天根本想不到去做的，因为太麻烦了
that we don't even think to do today because it would just be way too painful.
嗯，所以我觉得那其实是一个很有意思的机会点
Um, and so I think that that's actually a really interesting bucket of opportunity
适合做自动化，一个例子
for automation, a really an example
是我最近开始做的，我们有项目 channel，你知道
that I've kind of started doing these days is we have project channels, um, you know,
对应我们在做的不同产品，或者
for different products that we're building and, or, you know,
合作之类的事情等等。所以
partnership things or whatever. And so.
我其实开始做的是，为每一个 channel 都建一个
I'll actually, what I've started doing is actually set up for each of these channels,
Site，基本包含完整状态。差不多是一个项目总览
a, a site that essentially has the full state. It's almost a, a project overview
然后我让 Codex 基本每隔几个小时对每一个
and then I have Codex basically every couple hours for each of,
对每一个 channel 去把所有可能的，你知道
for each of these channels go and essentially get all possible, you know,
发生变化的东西或进行过的对话都抓过来
things that have changed or conversation that's happened
然后整合进整个 Site 里
and essentially integrate it into the overall site.
于是它就成了一个上下文来源
And so then it becomes this context source for.
供任何需要上手的人用，甚至我自己想看更新时也能用
Anybody that needs to onboard or on ramp or even for me if I want to see updates.
嗯，所以这类事情我们以前从没做到过这种程度
Um, so there's that where it's we were never doing anything on this level before,
但其实非常有用。对，这确实很聪明。所以
but it's actually very useful. Yeah, that's actually really smart. So,
于是它就成了 source of truth，对吧？
so that that becomes the source of truth, right?
因为，就像，因为，你知道，是的
Cause, like, so maybe has like, cause, cause, cause, like, you know, yeah,
在 Slack 上来回沟通、手动更新 PRD 太痛苦了
like going back and forth and slacking and manually updating a PRD is such a pain.
太烦人了，直接让 AI 来做就好了
Pain in the ass is is just like, just get AI to do it.
我觉得大家都心知肚明
I feel it was just a known thing among everybody
任何文档在你发布的那一刻基本就过时了
that any document is effectively immediately out of date the moment you ship it.
而现在我们其实可以做出相当及时的文档
And it's. But now we actually can create fairly up to date documents
会自我更新。是的，这样它们才真正成为有用的产物。哦
that are updating themselves. Yeah, only they actually become a useful artifact. Oh,
那个，那个真的太酷了
that, that. That's super cool.
对
Yeah.
什么？你都用 go 来做什么？你会像“搞定我的 OKR”那样用它吗？
What? What? What kind of things do you use go for? Do you like go like hit, hit my OKR?
不是。你都用 go 来做哪些事？
No. What kind of things do you use? Go, go, go for?
那你用它做过最疯狂的事是什么？
Well, what's the most out there thing?
对我来说，说实话，我就是一直用它，因为我觉得
I think for me it's honestly, I just always use it cause I think
我对延迟相当不敏感
that I'm fairly latency insensitive.
大多数任务，大部分我让 Codex 做的任务
Most tasks, for the most part, the tasks that I'm asking Codex to do, it's,
我更在意它能把事做完，而不是在意十分钟内完成
I just care about it completing it less than I do doing it in 10 minutes or something.
所以我会说我用它挺常规的，但是，嗯
And so I'd say it's a pretty standard thing that I'm using, but, um,
我会说重头戏往往是当我从零生成一个产物
I'd say the big ones are often when I'm generating from scratch an artifact
而我其实又没有那么多既定想法时
where I actually don't have as much opinions.
我是说，通常我会进去说“我想要的是这个”
I mean, often, you know, I'll go in and say this is what I want.
比如说我在生成一个 slide deck 或某种文档
Now, let's say I'm generating a side deck or some sort of DOC.
我大致清楚自己想要什么。于是就用语音来沟通
It's generally know what I want. And so then it's just using voice to communicate.
呃，你懂的，用转录，我会让它做，然后把想法一股脑倒出来
Uh, you know, transcription, I'll ask it to do it and brain dump,
但有时我会让 Codex 去做一些我自己都不知道答案的事
but then sometimes I'll ask kids to do things that I don't even know.
那种很开放式。嗯，那种情况我尤其会用它
And it's very open ended. Um, then I'll use roll especially for that
因为可以说，去把各处到底发生了什么彻底搞清楚
because it's okay. Go really figure out what's going on everywhere,
然后想出一个方案
then come up with an idea.
也许在动手之前先问我一下，然后再去做
Maybe ask me before you build it. Then go build it.
明白了？好。好的，兄弟，就剩几个问题了
Got it? Okay. Alright, man. Just a few more questions.
比如你有没有一套自己的 skills，还是你主要用 OpenAI 的 skills
Like do you have a personal set of skills or like do you mostly use OpenAI skills,
但比如说，你有没有一套 Rohan 个人的 skills，来体现你自己的品味
but like, do you have like a personal Rohan skills to apply your own taste
类似这样的操作，对吗？
and stuff like that or?
是的，我……其实我不这么做
Yeah, I. Yeah, I actually don't.
我一般用的是……我们其实在内部做了很多有意思的
So I typically am using so I mean we've actually built out a ton of interesting
插件，其中一些
thing plugins internally and actually some of them
我们还对外发布了，针对特定角色，比如
that we've shipped externally for specific roles, for example,
设计或财务之类的。但就我而言
design or finance and things like this. But for me,
我其实用 skills 用得很少
I actually am pretty light on the skills.
我觉得部分原因是我常常发现……
I think part of that for me is I often find that from.
对我来说，看看 Codex 在哪些地方会掉链子很有用
It's really useful for me to see where does Codex fall over
就是在它没有任何特定设置的时候
when it doesn't have any specific stuff.
呃，我是说，老实讲，也许是我
Uh, and I'm, I mean, honestly, maybe I'm just too, you know,
想用它做的事都太简单了
small brain on the things I'm trying to do with it,
但它做大多数事情通常都挺好的
but it's generally pretty good at doing most things.
不过有些时候，我用 skills 主要是为了定义
There are a few times, though, where I think what I use skills for is defining
工作流，也许可以这么理解
workflows is maybe one way to think about it.
通常我会说要么放进 skill，要么做成自动化，就像，好，酷
And often I would say it's either in a skill or an automation, but it's okay, cool,
我们刚在对话里花了 20 分钟做了这件事
we just did this thing in a chat for 20 minutes.
现在我大概每周要做几次
I wanna do this again probably a couple times a week now.
那就把它变成 skill 或做成自动化之类的。明白
Turn that skill or turn that into an automation or something like that. Got it.
明白。好的。明白
Got it. Okay. Got it.
呃，然后……你有没有那种，比较
Um, and then, and then, uh, do you have any just like, um, high,
高层面的使用 Codex 的建议，给那些还不太会用 Codex 的人，比如我，我
high level tips for using Codex for some of the more Codex fail people like I, I,
我记得 Jason 发过一篇文章讲他怎么用 Codex 的。呃，有些东西
I remember Jason published an article about how he uses Codex and. Um something.
第一条是，就一直在一个长期运行的 thread 里跟它对话
The first one was like, just like keep talking to it in a long running thread,
这一点我之前基本没做过。你有没有什么个人小技巧之类的？
which I didn't really do before this. Like do you have any personal tips or anything?
有，一个巨大的突破是我们最近发布了 Codex 现在可以
Yeah, well, one thing that was a huge unlock is we recently shipped Codex can now
控制 thread
control threads.
所以你可以有一个高层面的编排 thread
So you can kind of have a high level orchestrator thread
它实际上在调度其他 thread 之类的
that's actually spotting other threads and things that.
所以我觉得这绝对是用这个工具的好方式
So that's definitely, I think, a great way to use the tool.
对我来说，我最大的建议，或者说最大的突破，第一是
The, for me, I would say my biggest advice would be or the biggest unlocked is 1,
确保 Codex 接入了你所有的工具
make sure that Codex is integrated into all your tools.
有时候这可能需要构建自定义的 CLI 之类的
So sometimes that might require, you know, building custom CLIs and things like this,
但通常就跟我们有一个对应工具的插件一样简单
but often it's just, you know, as simple as we have a plugin for the tool
直接去接入就行。呃，然后我会说
and just go integrate it. Um, and then I would say,
而且很棒的一点是，即使
and then what's great though is even
它没有连上那个工具，你也常常可以直接用 computer use
if it doesn't have the tool connected, you can just use computer use often.
还有一点，说实话，就是好好想想你在做的所有事情
The other thing, I mean, is honestly just thinking through what are all the stuff
想想为什么 Codex 不能做，或者每次你遇到问题时
that you're doing and why can't Codex do it or every time you run into an issue or
要么就是——你让它做了吗？如果没有，那太好了，试一下就行
either it's like. Did you ask it to do it? If not, then great. Just try.
然后如果你试了它没做成，我觉得有些人
And then if you tried and it didn't work, then I think some folks,
很容易看到它没做对，然后就想，好吧
it's easy to see it not do something correctly and then kind of just be, great.
那我自己来做算了
That's I'll just do it myself.
但我觉得，如果你总是去问缺了什么
But it's, I think if you always ask the question of what was missing.
作为人，我们怎么知道它没做对？
As a human, how do we know that it didn't do the right thing?
很可能是我们有一些 Codex 没有的上下文或信息。对
Probably we have some context or some information that Codex didn't have. Yeah.
然后就是回答一个问题：Codex 缺了什么
And then it's just answering the question of what did Codex not have
再想清楚怎么把这些给它，好让它以后就有了
and then figure out how can I give it to it so that in moving forward it has it,
这样就会形成一种加速，让你把越来越多的事情
then it's kind of creates this acceleration towards just automating more
自动化掉。对，你
and more of the things that you're doing. Yeah, you.
也可以把一堆 skills 串成一整套工作流
Can also like string a bunch of skills together into like a whole workflow,
就让它一直跑下去。我，我发现这特别有用
just have it like keep, keep running. Like I, I found that super helpful.
对，我很好奇你，是什么让你产生了转变
Yeah, I'm, I'm curious for you, what changed the shift when you were low,
是什么让你转变的，或者那个"啊哈"时刻，觉得这真的很有用，或者 Codex
what made the shift for you or the aha moment of this feels really useful or Codex
确实能帮到我做事。呃，我
specifically can really help me with things. Uh, I,
我觉得让我震撼的是 browser use
I think what blew me away was like browser use,
我真觉得，我不知道是谁做的，但我真觉得它是
I really think I don't know who worked on it, but I really think it's like the No..
Codex 的第一大功能。呃，它完全把我震住了，比如
1 feature Codex has. Uh, so it totally blew me away because, for example,
甚至就这期播客，让它把我们正在聊的这份文字稿
even for this podcast ask like to turn this transcript
转成……我把它变成一堆素材，对吧
that we're talking about into I turn it to a bunch of assets, right,
比如newsletter帖子、社交媒体帖子，就是这一类东西
like newsletter post, like social post. Like all this kind of stuff.
我把这些内容发到各种不同的平台上，然后我
I got posted all these different platforms and then I,
我搭了一整套自动化流程
I built this like whole automation
它把一堆不同的skill串在一起
where it strings together a bunch of different skills.
比如它会根据我的示例，把这段文字稿变成一篇newsletter帖子
Like it turns this transcript into a newsletter post based on my examples.
有一个专门去除AI垃圾内容的skill，我会用它过滤掉很多水货内容
There's like a remove AI slop skill that that I run through a lot of slop stuff.
然后呢，还有另一个skill，负责发到所有的社交媒体平台上
And then and then, um, there's another skill to post all the social media platforms
因为像我说的，很多平台没有API
like, uh, a lot of it like I said doesn't have APIs
所以它就用browser use自己去搞定
so it uses browser use just figure it out.
最近我又做了一个skill，叫Hyper Frames
Recently I made another skill, this thing called Hyper Frames.
它可以根据文字之类的东西生成视频素材，对吧
So you can actually make video assets based on, like, text, right?
我还有另一个做幻灯片的skill，就是HTML幻灯片，真的太疯狂了
I have another skill to make slides, like HTML slides. It's just crazy, man.
你可以把这些全部串在一起。是啊
You can stream all the shit together. Oh, yeah.
我的意思是，我并不是什么都直接自动化
I mean, like, you know, I don't I don't just like auto automated stuff.
现在有一堆创作者，什么都像这样全自动化
Like there's a bunch of creators out there which is automate everything like this,
一直在批量产出大量垃圾内容
pump out tons of slop all the time.
所以我还是会检查这些内容。但它确实省掉了很多琐碎的杂活
So I actually check the stuff. But like it saves a lot of busy work, you know, really.
我觉得挺酷的，因为哪怕是对一个产品来说
I mean, it's cool because I think even for a product,
有意思的是，我们会聊到瓶颈
it's funny because we talk about the bottlenecks.
用Codex写代码更快，本来有那些SDLC上的瓶颈
You write code more fast with Codex. There's all these SDLC bottlenecks,
但有意思的是，我觉得接着又会在组织的其他环节
but then it's funny because I think there's then becomes even bottlenecks in other
出现新的瓶颈，因为你要交付这么多软件，对吧
parts of the org when it comes to shipping so much software, right?
比如说，我们发布产品的节奏太快了
Um, for example, we ship so much product at a pace
快到很难为它们制作营销素材
that it's hard to create marketing assets for them,
比如高质量的视频、demo之类的东西
really high quality videos and demos and things like this.
所以我们的devx团队，就是Ramon的团队，他们开发了一些skill
And so our devx team, you know, Ramon's team, they developed some skills, um,
用Codex来生成那种很不错的视觉图形视频
to actually use Codex to generate nice kind of visual graphic videos, um,
这样他们现在就能更快地做出demo之类的东西了
which so now they can actually ship demos much faster and things like this.
所以我觉得，每次出现瓶颈
So I mean I think it's like every time there's a bottleneck, it's like, you know,
解决办法就是想办法让Codex来帮忙打破它一点
the solution is just find a way for Codex to help unlock it a little bit.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊，我感觉这些模型的能力已经超过了大多数人的野心
Yeah. I feel like the models are already beyond kind of like most people's ambition
超过了大家觉得它们该做的事，我想这就是我的观点
of what they should be doing. It's just like, I think that's my point.
第一条建议，就是直接让Codex去试着做
The number one tip. Like it's just like ask coders to try to do it.
就是要坚持不放弃。对，对
It's just like, be persistent. Yeah, yeah.
你应该把目标定得比你觉得可能的荒谬10倍
You should aim for something that seems 10 x more ridiculous than you ever think it
它很可能能完成其中90%，那就很好了
could, and it probably can do 90% of it and it's okay, great.
然后我就需要重新把目标再拔高10倍
Now I need a reset to be 10 x more than that.
那你怎么看，哥们儿？你觉不觉得，因为我感觉
So what do you think, dude? So, so, like, do you think, uh, because I, I feel like, uh,
PM这个职业经历过一段挺尴尬的时期
the PM profession like has gone through like a troll where like, you know,
大家把很多岗位的PM当成跨部门对齐的秘书一样
people just like grow if like cross functional alignment secretaries like for for a
很多岗位都是这样
lot of role roles.
但我现在其实对PM挺乐观的
But I actually feel pretty optimistic about PM now
因为你们在发布的这些新工具
because of all these new tools that you guys are shipping.
你怎么看？你觉得这份工作会变得有意思很多吗
Like what do you think? Do you think it's gonna become a lot more fun
还是说对你来说可能已经很有意思了，对吧？
as a job or it probably already is for you, right?
是啊，我是说，我确实玩得挺开心的
It's just, yeah. I mean, I think, I mean, yeah, I'm having fun.
所以是啊，现在是个好时候。但我觉得，现在发生的一切
So, yeah, it's a good time. But I mean, I think, yeah, I feel everything
几乎让每一个岗位都更有杠杆效应，不只是PM，而是每一个岗位
that's happening only makes pretty much every role more leveraged, not even just PM, but every role.
它真正解锁的，是让你能做多得多的事
It's kind of like, I mean, really what it unlocks is being able to just do way more
更全面地端到端负责，能同时推进多得多的事情
and own the end to end way more and work on way more things.
我觉得这一点挺有意思的
I think what it and it it's like kind of interesting.
我会说AI，你能感受到AI带来的杠杆，也就是同样的事你能做得更快
I would say AI, you can feel AI leverage, meaning you can do the same thing faster.
但我其实觉得，从我们能做到的事情来看
But I actually think where we see what we've been able to do
在我待过的那些最AI化的公司，比如OpenAI和Cursor
and like the most AI pill companies I've worked at, OpenAI and cursor,
我们的运作方式并不是把同一件小事做得更快
it's the way that we operate is not doing the same thing, small thing faster.
而是做多得多的事情，而且每件都做得更快
It's actually just doing way more things and doing all of them faster,
相对于你拥有的人数来说
relative number of people you have.
所以我觉得，作为一个就是喜欢做有用工具
And so I think as a someone who just loves building useful tools
喜欢跟客户打交道的人，我也说不好
and working with customers and just, I don't know,
就是给人们提供让他们惊喜的、有用的体验
just delivering useful experiences to people that delight them.
能做多得多这样的事，太酷了，你几乎不受任何限制
It's cool to be able to just do way more of that and you're so unconstrained.
你知道，我觉得，真的
You know, I think, uh, there's literally,
我都记不清上一次是什么时候了
I can't remember the last time where it was.
现在真的不是"什么是可能的"的问题
It's literally not a question of like what is possible.
而是一切都有可能
It's just everything is possible.
而是"我们该做什么"，挺让人兴奋的
It's just like, what should we do? Um, pretty exciting.
是啊，他会把系统搭起来去做这件事
Yeah, he's gonna set up the system to do it.
是啊，不过，我觉得
Yeah, but, but like, but like, I, I, I think, I think, uh,
可能是个缺点也可能是个优点，就是你并不会
maybe a downside or maybe a plus is like you don't,
你其实并不会因此工作得更少
you don't actually end up working less.
你可能反而会工作得更多，因为你能做的事太多了，对吧？
You probably end up working, working more because it's so much stuff that you can do, right?
就像，是啊，我觉得
It's like, yeah, I mean, I think, yeah, I mean,
对我来说，工作得更少从来就不是一个验收标准
I wouldn't say for me it wasn't a acceptance criteria was to work less.
我是说，我一直都是这样
I mean, I've dealt with this, you know,
我一直是那种工作很多的人，不过，是啊
that always been someone who works a lot but I think um, but yeah, I mean,
我说不好，我觉得我们会看到一些有意思的转变
I don't know it's I think that we're gonna see some interesting shifts
随着这些工具越来越擅长自动化越来越多的事情，肯定会的
as these tools get better and better at automating more and more for sure.
好的，Rohan，我是说，向你和团队致敬
All right, Rohan, well, I mean, uh, yeah, kudos to you and team and it's,
你们真的把 Codex 扭转过来了
it's really, you guys really turn Codex around.
它大概是我最常用的工具了
It's like probably my number one tool.
那大家可以在网上哪里找到你
Uh, and, and, um, where can people find you online and, uh,
继续关注你们的进展呢？
keep following the journey?
我在 Twitter 和 LinkedIn 上，就搜 Rohan
Yeah, I mean, I'm on Twitter and LinkedIn. Just Rohan.
是啊，我时不时会发点东西
Um, yeah, I'm posting every now and then,
想让大家知道我们在发布什么
trying to just let people know what we're shipping.
不过，真的很感谢你请我来
But, um, yeah, I really appreciate you having me on
看你发的那些东西也很有意思
and it's been fun to see all the stuff you're posting.
我说不好，这真是一段有趣的旅程
And I don't know, it's been a, it's been a fun journey.
是啊，兄弟，我特别喜欢那些梗，比如大家老是在重置额度上限
Yeah, dude, I I love the memes like people resetting limits all the time
还有一些挺犀利的，我很喜欢
and also some of the stark too. I, I love the, I love it.
是啊，挺好玩的，因为我感觉我们经常其实是在 Slack 上沟通
Yeah, it's funny because I feel often we're just actually communicating on Slack or
抱歉，是在 Twitter 上
sorry, on Twitter.
有人发了反馈，就会有人@我，"嘿，你能看看 Twitter 上这个吗？"
Someone posts feedback and someone will tag me. Yo, can you look at this on Twitter?
是啊，我懂。这正是最好的团队会做的事
Yeah, I got you. Yeah, that's what the best problems teams do.
他们都活跃在 Twitter 上，兄弟，所以很合理。是啊，氛围很棒
They're all over Twitter, dude, so it makes sense. Yeah. No, vibes are great.
那，好了，兄弟。聊得很开心。是啊，谢谢你
So. All right, dude. Good chatting, man. Yeah. Appreciate it.